Sanisa: Good morning, everyone! My name is Putu
Sanisa Pascaline. Today on October 11th, 2020, we are
doing a meeting for fulfilling the 4th phase in our design
sprint by having a dialogue and asking for feedback from
kak Rahmat as an app developer of Kescatin, the app we
are evaluating. Please introduce yourself, Nin.
Anindyo: My name is Muhammad Anindyo.
Handini: My name is Handini.
Sanisa: Ok, we can start, can’t we?
Anindyo: Before I present the new design, I want to
explain what features that expand the business process
of this app. First, the onboarding feature, which is a
feature that asks the user to fill in data so that they will
get articles that match the data. Second, we added a
“learn more” feature to the result of pregnancy-worthy
check-up. Third, we revamped the pocket book view and
added a few illustrations. Lastly, fourth, we added a home
button to make user navigation easier. Let me begin the
design presentation. So, this is the loading menu. Then,
enter to the app profile and if we press “start” it will direct
us to the onboarding menu. Here, we input our data from
gender, age, pregnancy status, and disease history.
Then, the data is collected and will be tailored with the
existing article. If we are done, soon we will proceed to
the home menu. There are three menus. First, we try
“Buku Saku” (Handbook). Before, there were not any
images yet, but then we added them. Let’s choose
“Wedding Preparation”, then “Wedding Philosophy”. And this is the article. If you want to return to home, just press
the home button. Then, let’s try the “Pregnancy-worthy
Check-up”. Some of the views are also revamped. Let’s
set thalassemia as “none”. Then we check. The result is
successful. Let’s try the failed one. We choose as a
thalassemia sufferer. Turns out, it failed. We also added
the “learn more” feature which explains the disease that
affects our unworthiness. Then, it takes us to the
thalassemia article. Return to the home. The third menu,
the recommendation button to take us to the previous
tailored article. Done.
Sanisa: Yeay, done! All features have been explained by
Anin, now we are asking for feedback from kak Rahmat.
So, what is your first impression on this design?
Rahmat: Yes, it’s cool! Very cool! In terms of UI, it has
improved, moreover in the UX.
If this is submitted to the client, during the contract period,
there will probably be a lot of changes immediately. Will
immediately be revamped.
Sanisa: Wee, cool
Rahmat: Cool. Overall, it’s adding up. The UI and UX are
adding up. From the UI/UX that you guys made...
because this is your own exploration, isn’t it? Without any
request from clients?
Everyone: Yes, it is.
Rahmat: At that time (when having a contract with a
client), I did have a request from a client on what features
should be added so I couldn’t do too much improvisation.
Rahmat: … I also use open source so there’s limitations.
Open source is hard to modify. Hence, if this was
implemented, the revamping wouldn’t use that open
source. The problem is, if I keep using that open source,
and want to verify the embed open source (example: in
.jar extension in android studio) it’s hard to change. If you
want to revamp on your own, you have to create your own
module. So, the solution is search for another open
source or make it on your own. Due to time limits, I’m
using an already existing open source. I also want to
comment on the additions. First, there’s on boarding, the
preliminary data. For this app, the user is a couple so
minimum two persons. So, in the onboarding, it’s better
available for two persons too, example: there’s separated
data input for the male partner and the female partner
then there will be a recommendation. But, the onboarding
from your design is… a new, creative innovation. So,
there’s a new feature, “recommendation” from the
onboarding. Then, there’s an addition on “PregnancyWorthy Check-up”. When he clicks “check”, for example
when it fails, it can be continued to the article. That’s also
good. Actually, I really want to do like that, but the time is
too short and there is a lot of undergraduate thesis to do. For the small parts, like the background with gradient,
that’s so nice. Then, the illustrations are changed. There’s
the cute one in Pregnancy-Worthy Check-up, the tiny
shoes one. Then, in the article there's a home button, that
is so good so it’s easier to return from each page. Would
you like me to give the rating?
Everyone: Yes, for sure.
Rahmat: For business process improvement and the
UI/UX, I give 9 out of 10.
Anindyo: Thank you!
Handini: Good job!
Sanisa: Kak, is it really important to have the onboarding
feature?
Anindyo: Is it necessary?
Rahmat: It’s important, hence this is an educational app.
It’s so important to add that feature because it will be
more educational.
The purpose of making the app for the user is getting
better.
Sanisa: So, it fits, doesn’t it?
Rahmat: Yes, it does.
Sanisa: Alright, thanks, Kak for having fun along with an
interview with us. -- Once again, thank you. Anin, do you
have any closing words?
Anindyo: So, anyway, you always have to be successful,
and thank you for your time, also for allowing us to
evaluate the Kescatin app. And thank you for the
feedback and the guidance.
Sanisa: Come on Handini, give some words!
Handini: Yes, thank you so much for the heart-warming
feedback. We become more enthusiastic. That’s all,
thank you so much.
Sanisa: Is there any from you, Kak?
Rahmat: I can only thank you again for redesigning so I
know where the gaps and the lacks. Then, it is refined by
you guys.
Handini: Kak, you can see the process on Youtube.
Sanisa: Yes, you can. Later we will send the link. Maybe
that’s it, any addition guys?
Anindyo & Handini: Enough.
Sanisa: We close our meeting, ok?
Once again, thank you for kak Rahmat, and now we are
back to our activity and good bye!