Sanisa: Okay, good night everyone. Back again with us
from TEAM H! My name is Sanisa.
Anindyo: My name is Muhammad Anindyo.
Handini: And my name is handini
Sanisa: Okay, in this meeting today, October 3rd, 2020,
we will discuss the app that we want to evaluate. Because
we already have the app on our phone, we can
immediately begin the discussion.
Sanisa: Okay, we are opening the app. Up here, in the
home menu. Umm, from the front view, what are your
opinions about this app? But first, we want to explain what
Kescatin app is
Handini: So, Kascatin is an app for to-be-braids....
Anindyo: … to gain infos and consultation (about
marriage life).
Sanisa: What does Kascatin stand for? I forgot.
Handini: It stands for “Kesehatan Reproduksi Bagi Calon
Pengantin” (Reproductive Health for to-be-braids).
Sanisa: Well, that’s what we will evaluate.
Sanisa: So, how’s the opinion
Handini: I think it’s nice, the colors are brightly yellow.
Anindyo: Yes, it is.
Sanisa: Ok, now we’re moving to the next section, “Buku
Saku (Pocket Book)” section.
Anindyo: Wait!
Sanisa: Ok, we’re opening it.
Anindyo: Why is the color so plain? Only white… Should
we make square menu boxes per category? So, it will be
more beautiful, interesting.
Handini: Yes, we should. So, it won’t be too monotone.
Sanisa: Yes, it can be. Then, what else?
Handini: Well, what should we do more in this section?
Sanisa: What do you think, Nin?
Anindyo: I think we should give an illustration above the
menu, so it will be more attractive.
Handini: That’s nice! So the color isn’t that white or plain.
Then, I think the writing’s font is all the same and is too
thin. I can barely read it.
Sanisa: Sure, later we change the font to be bolder. Then,
for the illustration, we can make it ourselves or search for
free stock. There's a web called “Unsplash.com”, it
provides free pictures / illustrations. We can check it later.
Anindyo: Okay, work on it later, either use our own picture
or take it from the internet. So, we will remodel all the tiles
and add attractive illustrations. Done... it’s clear, isn’t it?
Sanisa: “Buku Saku (Pocket Book)” section, clear! We’re
continuing to the next section
Sanisa: Ok, this is “Cek Layak Hamil (Pregnancy-Worthy
Check)” section.
Handini: It says this is a pregnancy plan for a couple,
right? Maybe just try it!
Sanisa: Ok, I want to fill it. Hmm, to-be-braids? Yes. Ever
been pregnant? No. Age? Between 20-35. How tall am i?
Oh, 155. Weight? 55. Gee, there’s upper arm
circumference, how long am i? Maybe below 23.5.
Anemia? It asks for the hemoglobin levels, maybe above
12. Chronic disease? There’s no.... hemophilia?
thalassemia? Should these be explained? So we know
what hemophilia / thalassemia is or shouldn’t?
Anindyo: I think it should? So, it gives an explanation or
link for explaining the disease. The link is connected to
wikipedia, health web, or even better, Kemenkes’ official
website.
Sanisa: Oh, right! So it’s more reliable. Let me continue.
Then, no hemophilia. Male’s information? Also no. The
last, infectious diseases? There’s no too. Ok, ready to
chech! Wow, my condition is ready to get pregnant! It
told you to plan a pregnancy with your partner.
Handini: Please try to replace hemoglobin levels, upper
arm circumference, and pregnancy status.
Sanisa: Ok, let’s try it. Let’s try to replace…. upper arm
circumference… hemoglobin levels… Ouch, it says “
You are not advised to get pregnant. It’s too risky. You
get two warnings: upper arm circumference is too short
and hemoglobin levels are anemia.” It also gives you an
advice “It’s too dangerous for the mom and the fetus.” It’s
so cool! However, it’s still plain like it needs some
attractive things. Just try it!
Anindyo: Wait! Yeah, it’s still really plain. We will improve
some parts later.
Handini: Ok. Well, our objectives on this app are done,
aren’t they?
Anindyo: Yes, they are. I think.
Sanisa: So, after this, we immediately determine who are
the two persons that want to design, and later, we can
immediately make the solution design.
Handini: Ok, thank you!
Anindyo: Well, later, we don't change the information at
all from the overall information section. If possible, don't
change the essence of the existing definitions. So, only
change (improve) the design
Sanisa: That’s right! So, we don’t change the definitions.
Anindyo: Only the visibility and interaction control.
Sanisa: Interaction control! Well, looks like our meeting
has ended. Only up to those points that we can discuss…
Interruption:
Sanisa: Before this video ends, I want to add
some ideas that haven't been delivered yet.
We have the initiative to add onboard features. This
feature will ask users for common data (not the name,
email, etc.) and process it into suggestions / tips. So, we
will choose the age / gender / marital status which will be
given tailored advice from the existing pocket book. This
feature will be clearly seen in our design later. I think
that’s all for this interruption….
Sanisa: Ok, let’s close our meeting. Thanks for watching.
Goodnight! Good bye!