Sanisa: Goodnight everyone! My name is Putu
Sanisa Pascaline. Now, we have been visited by 3
passersby to be asked about their opinion for our
Human-Computer Interaction assignment. Ok,
introducing our team members.
Anindyo: My name is Muhammad Anindyo.
Handini: My name is Handini.
Sanisa: Firstly, we want to thank Sintya, aunt Vina,
and Sinta for taking up their time for us. Our
purpose is to invite all of you because we want to
redesign a deployed PlayStore app. We do it so it
will look more user-friendly. Can it be screenshared?
Anindyo: Yes, it will be screen shared. So, there
are two designs. First is Handini’s design and the
other is mine. So, we take neumorphism theme for
this design. What’s neumorphism? It is a theme
that gives an arising impression while showing up
the app’s content, so pleasing to the user’s eyes.
Then, let’s see the app prototype. So, this is the
loading menu before entering the main page. This
is the profile menu about the app’s profile. Then, if
we press this “start”, we will be entering the
onboarding menu. What’s onboarding? It’s like
sign-up / register, but it’s not just asking for data, it
also can be a tutorial to point the app’s features. Usually, when we’ve just downloaded an app,
there will be an onboarding tutorial showing up.
Then, onboarding also asks for user data so it can
connect with us. Example, when we first created
Facebook, we usually would be asked “import
contacts?”, “change profile?”, “people to follow...”,
etc. all of them are onboarding. Onboarding here,
let us begin… we will input our gender. Next,
select our age. Next, pregnancy status (skipped
for male users). Next, disease history. Then, the
data will be collected and will be tailored to the
article for us.
After that, we enter the home menu. There are 3
features. First, Buku Saku (Handbook), one of the
original app’s features. There are articles about
the bride's health. Let’s try to open “Wedding
Preparation”. In it, there are more subtopics. Let’s
try “Wedding Philosophy”. Then, we’re entering the
article. Then, we press the home button and go
back to the home. Next, we try “Cek Layak Hamil”
(pregnancy-worthy check). Here, female users can
check their pregnancy-worthiness. Let’s try this
with “none” (without thalassemia). Then, let’s
check. Apparently, it’s allowed. Let’s try again.
What if we fill in the data as a thalassemia patient?
Is it allowed or not? It turns out to not be allowed; it
suggests to not be pregnant due to thalassemia.
Then, why? Just press learn more, soon we will be
directed into the thalassemia article. Then, we go
back to the home. The third feature (new) is recommendation, which will bring us to the tailored
article before. Done. Maybe that's all from me.
Thank you.
Sanisa: Thank you Anin for the presentation, now
please hand this to Handini.
Handini: So, for my design, we are taking a simple,
yet certain theme. Different from the previous
design, I'm not using onboarding. So, after the
loading menu, it will look like this. If so, go directly
to the home. In the home, different from the
original app, I’m adding the “Search Article”
feature at the very top. Then, each feature like
“Search Article”, “Handbook”, and “PregnancyWorthy Check” are separated by black line so it
will look different. In the handbook, it will be
showing the article. There are categories for each
article. Soon, we click the article, it will take us to
the perspective category of the article. And then, it
will look like this. Different from the previous
design, it has a home button while I’m just a back
button. Below the home, there’s “PregnancyWorthy Check” It’s just simple for me. Just simple,
like this. Then, if it succeeds, it will look like this.
And if it fails, it will look like this. Here, I'm not
adding the “learn more” feature so the users won’t
know what thalassemia is, but if they want to, they
can just go back to the home. Because there’s a “Search Article” feature, the
users can just search what thalassemia is. That’s
all from me. Thank you.
Sanisa: Yeay! two members of our team have
presented. Now we immediately ask Sintya and
aunt Vina. You guys can introduce yourself first
Sintya: Start from me, my name is Sintya Putri.
I went to UNDIKNAS Bali in the third semester and
majored in accounting. Next to me, there's my
sister-in-law.
Vina: My name is Vina Amanda. I’m married and
already have 1 child.
Sanisa: Can you tell the choice between Anindyo
and Handini? Which one?
Sintya: For me, I prefer Anindyo’s design
because it’s easy to understand. It has a lot more
pictures than the Handini’s. And it looks more
attractive. And it's easier to navigate back to back.
Also, it really helps us to prepare our marriage. So,
we won’t be wrong in the future. Can be better
prepared and know better.
Sanisa: So, because there are more articles to be
read. From aunt vina maybe?
Vina: For me, I’m broadly the same as Sintya.
Because I’m just a commoner, I don’t really understand design so I’m preferring Anindyo's
design. I think it's so user-friendly.
Because, every time I see the button, it becomes
easier and satisfies me, the design is nice though.
Then, the gradation and the illustration color are
futuristic. Moreover, I am planning on my second
child so I think this app is really helpful to me.
Sanisa: Wow, thank you so much for the
feedback!Don’t forget to download the app on PlayStore.
Thanks to Sintya and aunt Vina, now we continue
to Sinta pebrianti. Introduction first, miss.
Sinta: Hello friends, hello UNJ students! My name
is Sinta Pebriyanti from the medical faculty of
Christian University of Indonesia. Still in the first
semester, in East Jakarta. For me, I prefer
Anindyo’s design. I think it’s simpler. The color is
not too flashy. For example, for an eldery person
whose eyes hurt when seeing a flashy color, I
think it’s hard for them so I prefer to Anindyo’s.
Because it’s simple, the visuals are also pleasing
to be seen. Then, it is more educative. Both are
educative, but Handini’s one needs to navigate
manually and it’s a bit complicated. So, I prefer
Anindyo's because it already has the (tailored)
article, just tap it (“learn more”). After that, for the
onboarding, I think that’s important for giving a
clear identity like age, gender, it’s clearer to
record. I think that’s all from me, more simple, more pleasing, not complicated, the article is easy
to find because we young adults think it’s easy to
navigate back to back. But for elderlies in their
30s, it must be complicated: “Oh, how do we go
back to this article?” That’s all from me. Thank
you.
Sanisa: Woah, thank you, future doctor for giving
great statements.
Maybe there’s a little bit of addition from me.
From me, after fighting in the design process I
think Anindyo’s design is more memorable, not
really great but endearing in our eyes. So, there’s
a lot of considerations between Anindyo and
Handini because they are my team members, but
in terms of user-usability and proximity, we still
choose Anindyo’s design. Because of the
explanations from Sintya, aunt Vina, and Sinta
they all are clear. Maybe Anin or Handini have
more explanation? Several statements before
closing?
Handini: From me, nothing.
Sanisa: From Anin?
Anindyo: I just want to say thank you for coming
here and taking time for voting. I hope this design
will be accepted by outside society.
Sanisa: Amin
Handini: Amin, thank you all!
Sanisa: Thank you Sintya, Sinta, aunt Vina,
everyone!
Everyone: You’re welcome!
Sanisa: Let’s close our meeting! We are closing.
Once again, thank you for taking your time. Good
night, have a good sleep, happy continuing
activities, thanks to be “disturbed”!